Rienow, Leona; Papers mss025
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Leona Train Rienow Papers
1856-1988
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
mss025
2.78 cubic ft.
This collection documents Leona Train Rienow's professional career as a writer. The papers contain a significant number of drafts of Leona Train Rienow's manuscripts, papers concerning her research for her books and articles, and correspondence files.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, in June 1988.
Biographical Sketch
Leona Train Rienow was born in Duluth, Minnesota in 1903, but moved when she was one year old to the mining site of Chisholm, Minnesota. She received a B.A. from the University of Chicago and her Master's from the University of Minnesota. In 1931, she married Robert Rienow while he was attending West Point. She toured Europe in 1948 and Italy in 1953. She also traveled on a tramp freighter around the Mediterranean visiting Cairo, Alexandria, Beirut, and Damascus. Her interests included birds and bird-watching, baking, camping, canoeing, touring, forestry, the environment, politics, photography, roses, cats, prehistory, and the Middle Ages.
Leona Train Rienow authored books, most of which were for children, short stories, and articles. Her books included The Bewitched Caverns (1948), The Dark Pool (1949), The Year of the Last Eagle (1970), and Unbottled Scotch (1987). She also co-authored a number of books with her husband including Our New Life with the Atom (1959), Of Snuff, Sin and the Senate (1965), The Lonely Quest: the Evolution of Presidential Leadership (1966), Moment in the Sun: a Report on the Deteriorating Quality of the American Environment (1967), Man Against His Environment (1970), and The Great Unwanteds Want Us: Illegal Aliens-too late to close the gates? (1980).
Leona Train Rienow died of a stroke in 1983 at Child's Hospital in Albany, New York. She was eighty years old.
Scope and Contents
This collection documents Leona Train Rienow's professional career as a writer. The papers contain a significant number of drafts of Leona Train Rienow's manuscripts, papers concerning her research for her books and articles, and correspondence files. Much of the correspondence concerns publishers and editors of various magazines and publishing houses.
Strengths of this collection include the many drafts of manuscripts that document the changes that Leona Train Rienow made to her works over a span of many years. Weaknesses of this collection include a lack of material on Rienow's personal life outside of her professional career as a writer and her environmental activism. There are also many whole newspaper sections, news clippings, and notes written on scraps of paper whose significance is often unclear. Also, this collection does not comprise drafts of all her books and articles.
Preservation concerns include yellowing and/or brittle paper which is often folded and/or wavy, foxing on the edges of some manuscripts, corners or pieces torn out of some pages, and fire damage.
Several collections in the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives provide further information on the environmental and political issues that were of concern to Rienow throughout her life. Of particular note are the collections of her husband Robert Rienow (UA-902.009), Environmental Advocates of New York (APAP-104), Nancy Papish (APAP-144), Environmental Clearinghouse, Inc. (APAP-180), and Vincent J. Schaefer (UA-902.010). For a complete list of related collections see the subject guides for Conservation and the Environment and Literature.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1 - Typescripts, ca. 1950-1955, Undated
Series 2 - Research Materials, 1856-1960
Series 3 - Correspondence, 1946-1988
All series are arranged alphabetically.
Literature; Conservation and the Environment; Women authors; American fiction--Women authors; Rienow, Leona Train--Manuscripts; Minnesota--Chisholm; Manuscripts (document genre); Research (document genres); Correspondence; Clippings (information artifacts); Rienow, Leona Train
- Typescripts, ca. 1952-1955; Undated; 1; 2 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of drafts of several books, short stories, and articles authored by Leona Train Rienow, many of which are undated. Drafts pertaining to her books include The Friar's Lantern; A Kingdom for Ethelfleda; Locusts; Mystery of the Midnight Fire; Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter; Mesaba Plunder; and River without Any End. Drafts of short stories include Bed and Breakfast; Cradle of Humanity; Fair on Morrow; Gekocht Aardappelen; Gory Glory; The Great Salt Age; Hospitality-Old World Style; I Dare You to Sleep in Your Own Guest Room; I Dare You to Sleep in Your Own Spare Room; It's the British Air!; Monuments by God; Peasoup and Snails; Peeking Gendarmes; Professor, Your Goodwill is Showing; Screwball Authorities: Our Idolatry of Big Names; Tourists Delight; You Can't Buck Tradition; and We Become Class-Conscious.
  - Bed and Breakfast, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Cradle of Humanity, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Fair on Morrow, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Preliminaries, 1959 June (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter I, 1959 June (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter II, 1959 June (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter III, 1959 June (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter IV, 1959 June (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter V, 1959 June (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter VI, 1959 June (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter VII, 1959 June (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter VIII, 1959 June (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter IX, 1959 June (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter X, 1959 June (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter XI, 1959 June (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter XII, 1959 June (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter XIII, 1959 June (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter XIV, 1959 June (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter XV, 1959 June (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter XVI, 1959 June (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter XVII, 1959 June (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Fleda, King Alfred's Daughter, Chapter XX, 1959 June (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter I, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter II, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - The Friar's Lantern Chapter IV, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter XIV, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter I, 1952 May (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter II, 1952 May (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter III, 1952 May (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter IV, 1952 May (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter V, 1952 May (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter VI, 1952 May (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter VII, 1952 May (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter IX, 1952 May (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter X, 1952 May (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter XI, 1952 May (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter XII, 1952 May (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter XIII, 1952 May (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter XIV, 1952 May (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter XV, 1952 May (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter XVI, 1952 May (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - The Friar's Lantern, Chapter XVII, 1952 May (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Gekocht Aardappelen, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Gory Glory, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - The Great Salt Age, 1961 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Title Page and Diagram, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter I, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter II, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 48)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter III, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 49)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter IV, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 50)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter V, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 51)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter VI, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 52)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter VII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 53)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter VIII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 54)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter IX, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 55)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter X, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 56)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter XI, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 57)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter XII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 58)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter XIII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 59)
  - The Haunted Orchard, Chapter XIV, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 60)
  - Hospitality-Old Word Style, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 61)
  - I Dare You to Sleep in Your Own Guest Room, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 62)
  - I Dare You to Sleep in Your Own Spare Room, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 63)
  - It's the British Air!, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 64)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Editor's Note, 1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 65)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Outline of Continuing Action, 1952 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 66)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Title Page and Chapter I, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 67)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter I, 1952 November (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 68)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter II, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 69)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter II, 1952 November (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 70)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter III, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 71)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter III, 1952 November (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 72)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter IV, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 73)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter IV, 1952 November (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 74)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter V, 1952 November (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 75)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter VI, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 76)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter VI, 1952 November (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 77)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter VII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 78)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter VII, 1952 November (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 79)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter VIII, 1952 November (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 80)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter IX, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 81)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter IX, 1952 November (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 82)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter X, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 83)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter X, 1952 November (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 84)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XI, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 85)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XI, 1952 November (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 86)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 87)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XII, 1952 November (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 88)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XIII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 89)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XIII, 1952 November (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 90)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XIV, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 91)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XIV, 1952 November (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 92)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XV, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 93)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XV, 1952 November (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 94)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XVI, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 95)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XVI, 1952 November (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 96)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XVII, 1952 November (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 97)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XVIII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 98)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XVIII, 1952 November (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 99)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XIX, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 100)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XIX, 1952 November (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 101)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XX, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 102)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XX, 1952 November (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 103)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XXI, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 104)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Chapter XXI, 1952 November (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 105)
  - A Kingdom For Ethelfleda, Discard Sheets, 1952 November (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 106)
  - Locusts, Chapter I, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 107)
  - Locusts, A, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 108)
  - Locusts, B, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 109)
  - Locusts, Chapter II, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 110)
  - Locusts, Chapter III, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 111)
  - Locusts, Chapter III, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 112)
  - Locusts, Chapter IV, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 113)
  - Locusts, Chapter IV, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 114)
  - Locusts, Chapter V, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 115)
  - Locusts, Chapter VI, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 116)
  - Locusts, Chapter VI, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 117)
  - Locusts, Chapter VII, 1953 November (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 118)
  - Locusts, Chapter VII, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 119)
  - Locusts, Chapter VIII, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 120)
  - Locusts, Chapter VIII, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 121)
  - Locusts, Chapter IX, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 122)
  - Locusts, Chapter X, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 123)
  - Locusts, Chapter X, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 124)
  - Locusts, Chapter XI, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 125)
  - Locusts, Chapter XI, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 126)
  - Locusts, Chapter XIII, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 127)
  - Locusts, Chapter XIV, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 128)
  - Locusts, Chapter XIV, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 129)
  - Locusts, Chapter XV, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 130)
  - Locusts, Chapter XVI, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 131)
  - Locusts, Chapter XVII, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 132)
  - Locusts, Chapter XVIII, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 133)
  - Locusts, Chapter XIX, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 134)
  - Locusts, Chapter XX, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 135)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXI, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 136)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXI, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 137)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXII, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 138)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXII, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 139)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXIII, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 140)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXIV, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXIV a, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXIV, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXV, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXV, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXVI, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXVI, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXVII, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXVII, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXVIII, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXVIII, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXIX, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXIX, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXIX a, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXIX a, 1953 April (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXX, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXXI, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXXI, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXXII, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXXII, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXXIII, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXXIII, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXXIV, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXXV, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXXVI, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXXVII, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXXVIII, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXXIX, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Locusts, Chapter XXXIX, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Locusts, Chapter XL, 1951 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Locusts, Chapter XL, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Locusts, Chapter XLI, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Locusts, Chapter XLII, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Locusts, Chapter XLIII, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Locusts, Chapter XLIV, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Locusts, Chapter XLV, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Locusts, Chapter XLVI, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Locusts, Chapter XLVII, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Locusts, Chapter XLVIII, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Locusts, Chapter XLIV, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Locusts, Chapter L, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Locusts, Chapter LI, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Locusts, Chapter LII, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Locusts, Chapter LIII, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Locusts, Chapter LIV, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Locusts, Chapter LV, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - Locusts, Chapter LVI, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - Locusts, Chapter LVII, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 48)
  - Locusts, Chapter LVIII, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 49)
  - Locusts, Chapter LIX, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 50)
  - Locusts, Chapter LX, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 51)
  - Locusts, Chapter LXI, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 52)
  - Locusts, Chapter LXII, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 53)
  - Locusts, Chapter LXIII, 1955 (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 54)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Author's Note, Title Page, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 55)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter I, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 56)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter II, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 57)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter III, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 58)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter IV, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 59)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter V, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 60)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter VI, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 61)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter VII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 62)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter VIII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 63)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter IX, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 64)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter X, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 65)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter X, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 66)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XI, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 67)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 68)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XIII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 69)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XIV, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 70)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XV, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 71)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XVI, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 72)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XVII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 73)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XVIII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 74)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XIX, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 75)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XX, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 76)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXI, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 77)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 78)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXIII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 79)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXIV, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 80)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXV, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 81)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXVI, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 82)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXVII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 83)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXVIII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 84)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXIX, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 85)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXX, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 86)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXXI, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 87)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXXII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 88)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXXIII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 89)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXXIV, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 90)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXXV, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 91)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXXVI, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 92)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXXVI a, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 93)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXXVII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 94)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXXVIII, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 95)
  - Mesaba Plunder, Chapter XXXIX, Undated (Box 3 (8-Subject Files), Folder 96)